Finding Aid for University of Michigan Assorted Videotapes, 1981-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University of Michigan Assorted Videotapes 1981-2005, 1991-2000
University of Michigan.
4 linear feet
2014127 Bimu 2
Artificially constructed collection of University of Michigan videotapes received from a variety of sources. Videotapes, mainly in VHS format, of University of Michigan events, symposiums, panel discussions, interviews, outreach and public service announcements as well as network news depictions featuring the University of Michigan. Includes Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy ground breaking and naming, Arthur Miller symposium, MLK Day events, and Y2K public service announcements.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was assembled from various sources.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
This collection was assembled by the Bentley Library from various University Departments and individuals.
Artificially constructed collection of University of Michigan videotapes received from a variety of sources. Videotapes, mainly in VHS format, of University of Michigan events, symposiums, panel discussions, interviews, outreach and public service announcements as well as network news depictions featuring the University of Michigan. Includes Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy ground breaking and naming, Arthur Miller symposium, MLK Day events, and Y2K public service announcements. The videos are arranged into of four series: Events, Interviews, Outreach and U-M Produced Videos, and News Depictions of U-M. Unless otherwise indicated, all items are in the VHS format.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Affirmative action programs--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Cantor, Nancy.; Ford, Gerald R., 1913-2006.; Miller, Arthur, 1915-2005.; Multiculturalism--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy.; University of Michigan. Martin Luther King, Jr. Symposium Committee.; University of Michigan. School of Music, Theatre & Dance.; Veltman, Martinus.; William Monroe Trotter House (University of Michigan); Year 2000 date conversion (Computer systems)
Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
- Events 1981-2005
  Events, 1981-2005 (2.25 linear feet), arranged alphabetically, consists of recordings of university events, including awards, commencements, convocations, and lectures.
  - 18th Annual Technical Education Program (TEP) Graduates and Award Recipients. Remarks by Rick Wagoner, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, General Motors Corporation. Detroit, MI May, 2005 (Box 1)
  - African-American Health: A Dream Deferred, Martin Luther King, Jr. Symposium, Dr. David R. Williams, BMC-1187 1998 (Box 1)
  - College of Engineering: Excellence in Staff Service Awards, B. Malinoski 1993 (Box 1)
  - College of Literature, Science, and the Arts: Commencement, Main Speaker: Carole Simpson May 2, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Conversation with Enid Sutherland & Alice Fulton, Host: Yopie Prins December 13, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Conversation with the President, WFUM undated (Box 1)
  - Conversation with University Leaders, WFUM December, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Conversation with Women Provosts October 6, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Daniel Libeskind: The Future of Memory December 7, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Dedication of the Leland I. and Mildred M. Doan Student-Faculty Lounge, School of Music Electronics and Recording Service, January 12, 1981, cassette tape (Box 1)
  - Diversity Litigation Media Relations Workshop with Nancy Cantor, Conducted by Bock & Associates, Inc. April 29, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Dr. Barbara Given, Dumas Chair Presentation December 11, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Freshman Convocation August 29, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Future of Government/University Partnership, The 1996
    - Opening Statements; Jerome B. Wiesner Lecture; Not What We Think: What We Haven't Thought Of", BMC-1038A (Box 1)
    - The Research University in National Science & Technology Policy, BMC-1038B (Box 1)
    - Outputs: Research and Education for the 21st Century, BMC-1038C (Box 1)
    - Inputs: Responsible Allocation & Stewardship of Resources, BMC-1038D (Box 1)
    - Exploring Principles & Expectations (Closing Session), BMC-1038E (Box 1)
  - Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy, Joan and Sanford Weill Hall Groundbreaking Ceremony November 12, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Gerald R. Ford School of Public Policy Naming Ceremony and Panel Discussion September 12, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Golden Apple Award for Outstanding Teaching, Dr. Carol Boyd's "Last Lecture" April 15, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Golden Apple Award for Outstanding Teaching, Professor Ralph Williams' "Last Lecture" March 16, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Gregory Howard Williams, Race Relations in the U.S. (Box 1)
  - Interim President Homer A. Neal Farewell 1996 (Box 1)
  - Keith Henley, M.D., 50 Years as a Physician at The University of Michigan undated (Box 1)
  - Let's Pick it Up, Joan Gillum, BMC-1148 1997 (Box 2)
  - Making of America Celebration, University Library, Speaker: Doris Kearns Goodwin March 12, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Event Co-sponsored by Library & Bentley Historical Library undated (Box 2)
  - Martinus J.G. Veltman 1999 Nobel Prize Winner in Physics, Public Lecture, October 22, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Miller Symposium, Arthur Miller Segments from October 26, 2000 Gerald Ford Comments at September 18, 2003 dedication of site for Ford School of Public Policy, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Miller Symposium, End of Q& A period and Arthur Miller October 26, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Myron Wegman, Public Health Pioneer November 16, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Nancy Cantor, Ph.D., CDC Speaker, Diversity in the Workplace: A Personality Psychologist's Perspective October 8, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Nancy Cantor, Michigan League November 14, 1999 (Box 2)
  - New Millennium: Is Higher Education Ready? Clifton Wharton, Jr., BMC-1131 April 10, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Office of the Vice President for Research, Distinguished Lecture Series on National Policy, Dr. M.R.C. Greenwood October 3, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Pamela Mitchell January 16, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Political Correctness and Academic Values, Roger Sutton, BMC-899 1994 (Box 2)
  - Ralph E. Gomory: New Opportunities...for Learning Outside the Classroom, Office of the President and the Dean of Academic Outreach, BMC-1115 1997 (Box 2)
  - Sally Fleming Master Class Series, Britton Recital Hall, BMC-1128 May 10, 1997 (Box 2)
  - Sarah Goddard Power Memorial Service March 27, 1987, 2 cassette tapes (Box 2)
  - School of Music, Dedication of the Britton Recital Hall October 27, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Service to Honor and celebrate the Life of Ralph Herbert November 17, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Special Regents' Meeting November 12, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Team Michigan Kick Off Rough Cut November 6, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Transportation Research Institute July 2000 (Box 2)
  - Trotter House 25th Anniversary undated (Box 3)
  - Vaclav Havel Award/Symposium/Press Conference September 5, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Weisner Symposium, Innovations in Undergraduate Education June 16, 1999 (Box 3)
  - William C. Richardson, Adding Value & Virtue: The New Challenge of Higher Education February 6, 1997 (Box 3)
  - William Cook Lecture, A. Bartlett Giamatti, Americans and their Games, January 31 -- February 2, 1989 (Box 3)
- Interviews 1996-1999
  Interviews, 1996-1999 (0.25 linear feet), arranged alphabetically, consists of interviews of U-M faculty and students.
  - Beyond Cultural Stereotypes: Interviews with Patients, Lynne Robins, Ph.D. and Patricia Barr, BMC-1066 1997 (Box 3)
  - Bollinger/Reynolds Interview October 25, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Nancy Cantor Interview, ISR History Project June 12, 1998 (Box 3)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Krenz Interview Offline Edit undated (Box 3)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Student Interviews 1996 (Box 3)
  - UROP Interviews Repeater Reel July 1996 (Box 3)
  - William D. Revelli Interview 50th undated (Box 3)
- Outreach and U-M Produced Videos 1991-2002
  Outreach and U-M Produced Videos, 1991-2002 (1.0 linear foot), arranged alphabetically, includes videos officially produced by the University of Michigan. These include videos produced to educate the University community and videos produced for public outreach. Of particular interest are videos relating to education on Y2K (Year 2000) compliance. Y2K videos include 3 public service announcements (PSAs) including the master 1 inch tapes of each PSA.
  - Department of Geological Sciences, A Tradition of Leadership August 22, 1993, Betacam SP) (Box 3)
  - Gerald R. Ford Biography undated (Box 3)
  - Institute for Research on Women and Gender, Mail: Daphne and Apollo Remade October 30, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Institutional Message, Fall 1996 (Box 3)
  - Managing Your Student Loans, Student Loans and Collections Office, BMC-1146 1997 (Box 3)
  - Mcard Adventure 1996, Betacam SP (Box 3)
  - Michigan Difference, The undated (Box 3)
  - Michigan Visiting Nurses: Bringing the U-M Health System Home undated (Box 4)
  - National Pollution Prevention Center for Higher Education: An Informational Video January 1994 (Box 4)
  - Oral History as Told by those who Lived it and Created it in Black Music in America 1988 (Box 4)
  - September 11, 2002 Remembrance, September 11, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Theatre at Michigan undated (Box 4)
  - Theory into Practice: The Production People August 21, 1991 (Box 4)
  - UMMC Disaster Committee, Disaster: A Planned Response, BMC-999 1995 (Box 4)
  - University Housing at the University of Michigan, Reconfiguring Your Building Block Furniture 1997 (Box 4)
  - University of Michigan and Y2K (Year 2000)
    - University of Michigan and Y2K: Cut 1: Scope and Diversity Cut 2: Academic Neighborhoods Cut 3 Unexpected Juxtapositions (VHS Dub from D-5 Master) 2000 (Box 4)
    - University of Michigan and Y2K: Cut 1: Scope and Diversity Cut 2: Academic Neighborhoods Cut 3 Unexpected Juxtapositions (Scratch Audio Track TC Burn VHS Dub from D-5 Master) 2000 (Box 4)
    - University of Michigan Y2K PSA Cut 1 of 3 Scope and Diversity (1" DUB from D-5 Master Stereo) 2000 (Box 4)
    - University of Michigan Y2K PSA Cut 2 of 3 Academic Neighborhoods(1" DUB from D-5 Master Stereo) 2000 (Box 4)
    - University of Michigan Y2K PSA Cut 3 of 3 Unexpected Juxtapositions (1" DUB from D-5 Master Stereo) 2000 (Box 4)
- News Depictions of U-M 1985-2003
  News Depictions of U-M, 1985-2003 (0.5 linear feet), arranged alphabetically, includes recordings of public news services depictions of the University of Michigan. The bulk of the series relates to the debates surrounding affirmative action.
  - 60 Minutes October 25, 2000 (Box 4)
  - ABC World News Tonight, American Agenda: Affirmative Action and College Admissions July 20, 1995 (Box 4)
  - C-SPAN2, Direct Student Loans, student Fiona Rose January 9, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Ford School of Public Policy Naming Ceremony and Press Conference November 18, 1999 (Box 4)
  - NBC Dateline: U-M Affirmative Action Case June 6, 2003 (Box 4)
  - NBC-TV, Today (Newscasts and commercials removed) October 17, 1985 (Box 4)
  - News and Information Service, B-Roll & Sound Bites on Affirmative Action at University of Michigan August 1999 (Box 4)
  - WXYZ-TV Detroit, Affirmative Action Spotlight "404312" undated (Box 4)